Divya Sharma

Product Compliance Sr. Associate

Phone: 8794420209

Email: dsdivsharma5@gmail.com

Key skills

Interpersonal skills, Communication

Communication, Tally, MS Office

Time management

Product and service knowledge

Languages

Hindi, Nepali, English

Education:

Masters in Commerce | Indira Gandhi National Open University (2018)

Bachelors of Commerce (Accountancy Hons) | St. Anthony's College (2015)

MBOSE XII | Gorkha Pathsala Higher Secondary School (2012)

MBOSE X | Mawprem Modern Higher Secondary School (2010)

Summary

Goal-oriented Professional with 3.5+ years of experience and a Proven knowledge of security operations, Compliance, pricing and preferred Customer Management. To achieve high carrier growth through a continuous learning process and keep myself competitive and dynamic with the changing scenario of the world. I aspire for a challenging position in an organization where I can enhance my skills and strengthen them in conjunction with organizations' goals.

Experience

Product Compliance Sr. Associate | Amazon Development Center / March 2018 till date

- Ensure that the imported Products have been tested in certified laboratories and that they comply with the legal requirements of the Importing Country.
- Classify Products based on their potential hazardous risk, for regulatory storage and transportation Purposes.
- Take appropriate actions in-order to protect customers from recalled or unsafe products.
- Identify and Remove from the website products that violate our Restricted Products policies and pro-actively satisfy Amazon's Regulatory Obligations for these Products.
- Implemented Regulatory guidance Procedures.
- Completed and reported on product impact assessments.

VCM Associate / Amazon Development Center / January 2017 till March 2018

- Strengthened vendor relationship and enhanced revenue streams by applying business development opportunities for North America (US/CA) and Australia.
- Helped to research, vet and onboard new vendors, set up contracts and establish connections.
- Achieved optimal goals by executing negotiations strategies for prices and services.
- Assessed Vendor Services for compliance with Company Policies.
- Received inbound phone calls and emails from vendors for Purchase Orders placed and shipments purpose.
- Helping the vendors to set up EDI Services for the vendors of North America and Australia.

Accountant | Gorkha Pathsala Higher Secondary School | May 2015 – July 2016

- Responsible for all aspect of accounting cycle such as debtor and fee management, financial reporting and development, ledger Management.
- Analyze figures, knowledge of accounting principles.
- Complete all regulatory, educational and general compliance requirements and return as they fall due.